# Aidan Tilgner

WEB DEVELOPER

aidantilgner02@gmail.com +1 (503) 200-7472 aidantilgner.dev linkedin.com/in/aidan-tilgner github.com/AidanTilgner

As a software developer, I strive to build technology that improves people's lives. That is why on top of my day job, I work vigorously on a multitude of side-projects that I believe advance that goal. Because of this, not only has my experience grown greatly over my last couple of years as a developer, but my passion has grown as well. It is important to me to work for a company that shares my passion and values.

#### EXPERIENCE

## Web Developer, Full Stack | Digital Strata

August 2021 - Present | Remote

- Developed complex multitenant and enterprise web applications with a high focus on data preservation and very fast turnaround times.
- Leveraged industry standard technologies such as React, Laravel, and Typescript to write readable, maintainable, and performant code.
- Communicated with a diverse client base to convert specific project requirements into various innovative software solutions.

# **Computer Science Tutor | Wyzant**

July 2021 - Present | Remote

- Worked with a diverse set of students to further their knowledge and understanding of computer science and software development.
- Provided students with digestible, coherent, and productive online lessons to equip them with the tools they need to further their careers.

### **EDUCATION**

# BrainStation | Diploma Recipient, Web Development

FEB 2021 - MAY 2021 | Remote

Over the course of around 450 total hours, I learned web development technologies, concepts, and best practices through a variety of sprint-based, professional-grade projects, taught by industry professionals.

# Sprague High School | High School Diploma

SEP 2017 - JUNE 2021, Salem, OR

At my high school I took two, semester-long courses on basic web design and development, using JavaScript and Bootstrap. This pointed me in the direction of web development as a career.

### SKILLS

Frontend - React, Typescript, Svelte, CSS Frameworks, Component Libraries

Backend - Laravel, PHP, Golang, Express.js, Node, Python

Database - MySQL, Surreal DB, MongoDB, Sqlite3

#### **PROJECTS**

GitHub - <a href="https://github.com/AidanTilgner">https://github.com/AidanTilgner</a>

Portfolio – <a href="https://www.aidantilgner.dev/home">https://www.aidantilgner.dev/home</a>

Component Tracker – <a href="https://github.com/AidanTilgner/component-tracker">https://github.com/AidanTilgner/component-tracker</a>
Natural Language Processing API – <a href="https://github.com/AidanTilgner/NLU API">https://github.com/AidanTilgner/NLU API</a>
Speech Recognition API – <a href="https://github.com/AidanTilgner/speech-api">https://github.com/AidanTilgner/speech-api</a>
Onyx Systems AI Assistant Framework – not yet public, inquire personally